Contact

36lima@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kelly-scottnetterville (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Responsive Web Design
Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
JUnit

Certifications

Tools of the Trade: Linux and SQL

Microsoft Certified: Azure

Fundamentals

Connect and Protect: Networks and

Network Security

Play It Safe: Manage Security Risks

Foundations of Cybersecurity

Kelly Netterville

Software Developer with Security Focus || Continuous Learning is a Passion || Experienced IT Professional || Proud US Army Veteran (1988-1997).

Fairfield Bay, Arkansas, United States

Summary

Whether it's learning new languages, playing music, or learning how to fly a helicopter, I love a challenge, especially one that exposes me to new concepts and ideas.

I began my career in technology in the Army as a fresh-faced 17-year-old. After getting out and rejoining civilian life, I continued that path and progressed from a software test role to Management and, then into software development, network engineering, and, most recently, security. I am privileged to have enjoyed a wide range of roles, technologies, co-workers, and amazing mentors.

Whether it's as a new team member, a technical SME, or in a leadership position, my goal is always to provide a positive impact, focus on customer and stakeholder satisfaction, and never stop learning and growing.

Experience

Calian Group Security Operations Center Analyst - Tier 2 February 2024 - Present (1 year 5 months) United States

Tech Elevator
Java Development Bootcamp Student
October 2023 - January 2024 (4 months)
National Live Remote

Currently enrolled as a Java coding bootcamp student at Tech Elevator.

* Capstone Project to Emulate Vending Machine functionality using object oriented principles.

* Working through self-study in parallel with class to refresh knowledge on Ruby and Rails.

Kandy Communications, an AVCTechnologies company 2 years 10 months

Senior Manager, Cloud Security September 2021 - October 2023 (2 years 2 months) Morrisville, North Carolina, United States

- * Built/Trained Security Operations Team
- * Primed Incident Response from Security Operations and contributed to ongoing process evolution.
- * Responsible for vulnerability scans and vulnerability management across multiple data centers globally.
- *Drove vendor selection process (including product evaluations based on cost and functionality) for various security related tools and mSOC.

Kandy Network Architect

January 2021 - September 2021 (9 months)

Morrisville, North Carolina, United States

- * Provided 24/7/365 Network Engineering Support for 8 Global Data Centers.
- * Designed and Implemented customer interconnects and core networks across all data centers.
- * Trained and mentored network engineering team members.

Genband

NUViA Operations Engineer

September 2013 - January 2021 (7 years 5 months)

Research Triangle Park, NC 27706

Implementation, Design, and Support of a global Unified communications network.

- * 24/7/365 Support across all global Data Centers.
- * Worked with diverse team to plan and execute multiple data center relocation without impacting customer experience including customers in law enforcement and emergency services.

Cisco Systems

7 years 5 months

Operations Management

May 2010 - August 2013 (3 years 4 months)

Operations Management for Engineering Infrastructure Services.

- * Project Management multiple independent projects related to lab tools
- * Worked with Financial Analyst to manage contract resources (funding, hiring, termination, interviewing, vendor management and selection).

Solution Test Engineer September 2009 - May 2010 (9 months)

- * Executed solution test on linecard based Video quality monitoring on the ASR9000 and 7600 platforms. * Verified multiple video quality metrics on various multicast video streams (H.246, MPEG-2, SD and HD, compressed and uncompressed).
- * Performed lab config to setup MPLS Tunneling test environment and worked with larger team to execute related testing.

Verify results to using industry tools metrics (IneoQuest, Anue, Ixia)

Business Operations Manager - NSITE April 2006 - December 2009 (3 years 9 months)

- * Managed NSITE Technical Writing team responsible for generating customer facing documentation for Cisco Validated Solutions.
- * Managed NSITE web development team responsible for internal tools related to lab operations.
- * Led daily business operations (financial tracking, program reviews, integration with partner organizations, and driving tools and process innovation).
- * Identified and closed on non-traditional funding source that resulted in \$18k of additional funding resulting in saved jobs.

Project Lead - Managed Services (VoIP) Solution Test April 2006 - August 2008 (2 years 5 months)

Project Management and Technical lead for solution test of Managed Services VoIP project.

- * Execute System level test for Cisco BTS10200 and related VoIP solution as a member of the larger test team.
- * Identify, track and validate issues found during test process.

Nortel Networks

Project Lead - CS2K Solution Test April 2004 - May 2005 (1 year 2 months)

* Team Lead and project manager for CS2k solution test. Lead team of engineers responsible for writing and executing test plans for Nortel's VoIP Call Server 2000.

- * Testing focused on system capacity, reliability, and scale.
- * Responsible for helping drive defect resolution and solution quality improvements.

US Army

36L MOS - Data and Voice Communications (Operations/Maintenance) 1989 - 1997 (8 years)

Education

Tech Elevator

Java Web Application Development Bootcamp · (October 2023)